Using SQLI makes it easy to delete, update, and insert rows using highly
expressive queries. One can even add new columns as you revision your database.
It's not a surprise that just about popular app makes some use of SQLI to
Android. It's a very popular and important component of the Android solution.
Android also provides a huge set of helper functions to make working with
databases easy, including functions to automate query building.
Display ListView is populated by queries and even compile statements. For
more information about databases in Android, see the instructor nodes. One thing
that I wanted to mention is that we're teaching you the fundamentals of how to
build database in a content provider on Android. The idea is that once you
are done with this class, you'll have a good understanding of how it all works,
even if you end up using a library to help build your database and
content provider in your future applications. That's it for
a brief intro into storage on Android. If you want to learn more,
go to developer.android.com and search on Data Storage.